<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: WinRT | Developing on Staxmanade]]></title>
  <link href="http://staxmanade.com/blog/categories/winrt/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://staxmanade.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-18T11:28:56-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://staxmanade.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Jarrett]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing ToTypeScriptD – Automatic TypeScript Definition Files for C++/CX or .Net Assemblies.]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2013/10/introducing-totypescriptd-automatic/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-31T22:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2013/10/introducing-totypescriptd-automatic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<p>If you’re unfamiliar with <a href="http://typescriptlang.org" target="_blank">TypeScript</a>, I’d highly recommend checking it out. <strong>It’s my new preferred way to write JavaScript based applications.</strong></p>  <p>If you write an application in TypeScript and need to interact with an external set of either JavaScript or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%2B%2B/CX" target="_blank">C++/CX</a> dependencies then you will quickly find that you are going to be mucking with some TypeScript Definition files and the more you take a dependency on the WinRT runtime the more type definitions you probably need to manually create.</p>  <p>It’s true that the TypeScript team has created a set of TypeScript Definition files for WinRT and WinJS, but I <a href="https://typescript.codeplex.com/discussions/462409" target="_blank">couldn’t get any comment</a> as to how they were generated. And the more I looked into what was provided, the more I realized that there were inconsistencies and inaccuracies that were not good. Which led me to believe that they weren’t working on a super-secret tool to automatically generate these for us.</p>  <h3>What is <a href="https://github.com/ToTypeScriptD/ToTypeScriptD" target="_blank">ToTypeScriptD</a> ?</h3>  <p><a href="https://github.com/ToTypeScriptD/ToTypeScriptD" target="_blank">ToTypeScriptD</a> is a quick little attempt at automatically taking the type system provided to us by a C++/CX winmd or .Net assembly file and projecting that into a set of TypeScript Definition files. This tool can basically take anything that is <a href="http://www.ecma-international.org/publications/standards/Ecma-335.htm">Ecma 355</a> Common Language Infrastructure (CLI) and spit out a .d.ts file for you automatically.</p>  <h3>Why would I need this?</h3>  <p>In the <a href="https://github.com/ToTypeScriptD/ToTypeScriptD#can-you-tell-me-why-i-would-use-this" target="_blank">project readme</a> I describe two use-cases that I know of (so far).</p>  <ol>   <li>If you build a 'Modern' (come on, we still call it Metro) Windows 8 app with <code>WinJS</code> and want to leverage <code>TypeScript</code>, wouldn't it be nice to get a set of TypeScript Definition files that reflect the native API's you're calling in the platform without manually creating the definition files?       <br></li>    <li>Say your building an MVC/WebAPI server application. It would be useful if your C.I./Build system could generate a set of TypeScript interfaces that were based on the server objects used to render your JSON API. This can be useful for client side JavaScript/TypeScript libraries that need to consume these objects and also provide a simple way to document the format of the input and output API response objects. </li> </ol>  <h3>How do I get the project and start using it?</h3>  <blockquote>   <p>Before you install the tool and dive in head first, I would like warn you that I have only been working on this for about 2 weeks (in my off-hours) and there is going to be lots of room for improvement. But it’s currently generating a solid set of .d.ts files for .winmd files.</p> </blockquote>  <p>Head over to the <a href="https://github.com/ToTypeScriptD/ToTypeScriptD" target="_blank">project home page</a> and check out the <a href="https://github.com/ToTypeScriptD/ToTypeScriptD" target="_blank">Readme</a> for some quick-start information.</p>  <p>I’d would love to hear feedback. If anyone is interested in helping out, you can submit new issues or review the open issues list and start submitting pull requests.</p>  <p>Happy TypeScripting!</p>  </div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
