<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Developing on Staxmanade]]></title>
  <link href="http://staxmanade.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://staxmanade.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T22:36:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://staxmanade.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Jarrett]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 5 - Fix Links]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-5-fix-links/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-5-fix-links</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>

<p>Once you&rsquo;ve ported your content into Octopress there were several steps I used to fixup links. The two types of links I cared about at this stage were:</p>

<ol>
<li>Cross-Post links (where I referenced one of my other posts)</li>
<li>Broken links.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Cross post links</h2>

<p>I used a text editor and some command line magic to search for <code>http://staxmanade.blogspot.com/</code> and replace it with <code>/blog/</code> so that my cross-referencing posts could link to a relative version of the blog instead of the full blogspot domain.</p>

<p>Depending on how you configure your <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/permalinks/">permalinks</a> you may need to do some more link manipulation. I had to search <code>.html</code> at the end of my cross-referencign posts and be sure to delete it since my old reference would look like</p>

<pre><code>http://staxmanade.blogspot.com/2013/12/format-your-net-exceptions-to-see.html
</code></pre>

<p>but now should link to</p>

<pre><code>/blog/2013/12/format-your-net-exceptions-to-see
</code></pre>

<p>If you&rsquo;re on Windows and not interested in figuring out a <code>PowerShell</code> or other command to quickly search and replace, a friend of mine <a href="http://programmerpayback.com/about/">Tim Greenfield</a> has a great utility GUI tool for easy <a href="https://seeker.codeplex.com">search and replace</a>.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t recall exactly what I did, I think I either used <code>sed</code> or a python command on my Mac for the initial search/replace. I&rsquo;ll let you figure out the rest of how to get that task done.</p>

<h2>Fix broken links</h2>

<p>Once you&rsquo;re done fixing up cross-post links, we want to make sure we didn&rsquo;t mess anything up, and while we&rsquo;re at it, fix any old or out-dated links.</p>

<p>One great feature of <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> is that we can run the site locally and use a spider tool to search for broken links.  Run <code>rake generate</code> and <code>rake preview</code> locally to browse your site.</p>

<p>I used the <a href="http://peacockmedia.co.uk/integrity/">Integrity link checker</a> on my Mac to search the <code>http://localhost:4000</code> site locally. There are lots of these tools out there, so feel free to use what you feel happy with.</p>

<p>This was a great exercise. Not only debugging any <em>oopsies</em> from the above cross-post fixup step, but allowed me to find any external links to blogs/images/etc that were out of date. I wasn&rsquo;t able to fix up all of my external links, but that&rsquo;s the way of the web unfortunately. I haven&rsquo;t done it yet, but have consider going back and linking the out-dated links to a version out on the <a href="http://web.archive.org/">Way Back Machine</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 4 - Import Content Into Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-4-import-content-into-ctopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-4-import-content-into-ctopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>

<p>In the <a href="/blog/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-2-setup-octopress">previous post</a> I discussed how to export your blog content from BlogSpot. Now that you have all of your content into a single <code>.xml</code> file, we need to translate that into the files and format that Octopress blog expects.</p>

<h1>Translate export <code>xml</code> to Octopress posts</h1>

<p>Thanks to a ruby script found in a <a href="https://gist.github.com/juniorz/1564581">gist</a>, it&rsquo;s fairly easy to get going provided you are able to leverage all the gem dependencies with your installation of ruby. On Windows this is tricky although fortunately there are tools like <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/yari">yari</a> to help out.</p>

<ol>
<li>Download and save one of these <a href="https://gist.github.com/dnagir/1765496/forks">gists</a> somewhere and call it <code>BloggerImporter.rb</code></li>
<li>Note: there are a number of forks of the script &ndash; if one doesn&rsquo;t work, browse other changes and see if something fits your needs.</li>
<li><p>From the command line go to a temporary folder and execute</p>

<p> <code>ruby {pathToImporterFile}/BloggerImporter.rb '{PathToBloggerExport}/blog-03-19-2014.xml'</code></p>

<p> When I tried it on my windows machine I received the following error. Sorry Windows folks, I don&rsquo;t have answers for every scenario here &ndash; I just jumped over to my Mac and tried again. I remember first trying this like a year ago and ran down a similar rat-hole trying to get this dependency to work which is probably why I didn&rsquo;t port it back then. I&rsquo;m sure it&rsquo;s possible, but wasn&rsquo;t worth my time (since it works on my mac and was a one-time task).</p>

<p> <code>ruby
 C:/Ruby193/lib/ruby/site_ruby/1.9.1/rubygems/custom_require.rb:36:in `require': cannot load such file -- nokogiri (LoadE
 rror)
         from C:/Ruby193/lib/ruby/site_ruby/1.9.1/rubygems/custom_require.rb:36:in `require'
         from BloggerImporter.rb:2:in `&lt;main&gt;'
</code></p>

<p> (One possible issue noted by a colleague: the ruby script requires a gem, <a href="http://nokogiri.org/">Nokigiri</a>, which is not supported on Windows by Ruby 2 at the time of this writing. This can be circumvented by either reinstalling Ruby 1.9.3 or by leveraging a tool like yari which allows you to pick the version of Ruby you wish to leverage with a script &ndash; a helpful StackOverflow answer exists <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/17318410/64">here</a>.)</p></li>
<li><p>You should now you have your content.</p>

<p> After you&rsquo;ve run the <code>BloggerImporter.rb</code> command you should have at least two folders in your temporary folder.</p>

<p> <code>
 ~/code/temp&gt; ls
 _drafts     _posts    BloggerImporter.rb
</code></p>

<p> I didn&rsquo;t end up caring about anything in my <code>_drafts</code> folder, but the <code>_posts</code> folder is full of gold. This contains all of your exported content now broken out into a separate file per post in the form of <code>{year}-{month}-{day}-{title}.html</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>Copy this content into the Octopress blog folder under <code>source/_posts/</code></p></li>
<li>At this point you&rsquo;ve successfully ported your content into your Octopress blog. Make sure you take tiny steps and <code>git commit...</code> the changes you care about along the way&hellip;</li>
<li>Use <code>rake generate</code> and <code>rake preview</code> to see if it worked.</li>
<li>If your preview looks right use <code>rake deploy</code> to put your changes on github.</li>
</ol>


<p>Hopefully it all worked out and you&rsquo;re looking at your new Octopress blog with your old content all there. If I recall when I went through this process, there was one HTML file that <code>Jekyll</code> had issues compiling. I probably just modified the post or deleted somethign that wasn&rsquo;t necessary (I can&rsquo;t recall anymore) but it was quick to work through.</p>

<blockquote><p>side note: When I initially tried getting <a href="http://disqus.com">Disqus</a> to work after this and had trouble. <strong>Turned out this was because in the YAML metadata in each post <code>comments: false</code></strong> :)</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 3 - Export BlogSpot Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-3-export-blogspot-content/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-3-export-blogspot-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>

<p>Thanks to Google for allowing us to <a href="https://support.google.com/blogger/answer/97416?hl=en">export our own content</a> and providing an easy way to get it all in one download. If we had to go manually read each item in an atom feed or web scrape the content off of a web page, this small series would be more like a novel&hellip;</p>

<h1>Steps to export content.</h1>

<ol>
<li>Log in to your [BlogSpot.com(<a href="http://BlogSpot.com">http://BlogSpot.com</a>) admin portal</li>
<li>Go to the <code>Settings</code> tab</li>
<li>Select the <code>Other</code> option under Settings</li>
<li>Under Blog tools select <code>Export blog</code></li>
<li>Save the file somewhere safe so we can refer to it later</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="/images/posts/blogger_settings.png" alt="Blogger Settings" /></p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s in this export file?</h2>

<p>This file contains the raw content and metadata around each of your blog posts. You won&rsquo;t get any of your images, but all of your original blog images are probably hosted on external sites. This is next on my list of things to add to the port-list (and will possibly extend this series even more). I would like to download each of my images locally, save them to my Octopress <a href="http://github.com/staxmanade/staxmanade.github.io">git repo</a> and update my posts to link to the local versions of the images (but that&rsquo;s lower on the priority).</p>

<p>Here is a snippet of a single entry from the exported file. In later posts we&rsquo;ll delv deeper into this to extract metadata an setup redirection from BlogSpot to our new blog.</p>

<h2>Sample Entry from Blogspot Export File</h2>

<p>```xml
  <entry></p>

<pre><code>&lt;id&gt;tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4726251688144615011.post-7515836382847059837&lt;/id&gt;
&lt;published&gt;2013-12-18T19:50:00.001-08:00&lt;/published&gt;
&lt;updated&gt;2013-12-18T19:50:18.725-08:00&lt;/updated&gt;
&lt;category scheme='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind' term='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post'/&gt;
&lt;title type='text'&gt;Format your .Net exceptions to see the StackTrace.&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;content type='html'&gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;TL;DR&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Check out a dinky little &amp;lt;a href="http://staxmanade.github.io/ExceptionMessageBeautifier" target="_blank"&amp;gt;Exception Message Beautifier&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; site I threw together so you can quickly format .net exception messages and easily see the StackTrace.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Go to the site: &amp;lt;a href="http://staxmanade.github.io/ExceptionMessageBeautifier" target="_blank"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font size="4"&amp;gt;CLICK HERE&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Background&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Over the years, I’ve worked on projects where application exceptions were saved to a SQL database. When querying the logs in Visual Studio or in Sql Management Studio’s table view, I would get a result-set that would not let me copy/paste and review the StackTrace easily. The tool always seemed to leave out the new line characters just like below.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;   &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;System.Exception: Hello Exception!   at TestExceptionGenerator.Spike.GetException() in c:\Code\personal\DotNetExceptionMessageFormatter\TestExceptionGenerator\Spike.cs:line 22   at TestExceptionGenerator.Spike.b__0() in c:\Code\personal\DotNetExceptionMessageFormatter\TestExceptionGenerator\Spike.cs:line 13   at TestExceptionGenerator.Extensions.GetExceptionString(Action action) in c:\Code\personal\DotNetExceptionMessageFormatter\TestExceptionGenerator\Spike.cs:line 34&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Now, I know there are ways to get around this, like exporting to CSV, or setting up the query results to return in text view instead of table view. However, when you’re in the heat of tracking down a bug and don’t feel like you have time to find the settings dialog or open up you’re a text editor like &amp;lt;a href="http://notepad-plus-plus.org/" target="_blank"&amp;gt;NotePad++&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and enter a search/replace as I show below over and over with each exception message you review.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://lh6.ggpht.com/-FGWJCcb9iUo/UrJs8rxtvqI/AAAAAAAAAik/uWK5NHFfU18/s1600-h/image15.png"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img title="image" style="border-left-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px; background-image: none; border-bottom-width: 0px; float: none; padding-top: 0px; padding-left: 0px; margin-left: auto; display: block; padding-right: 0px; border-top-width: 0px; margin-right: auto" border="0" alt="image" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/-Eo5EyWOkIm0/UrJs9Dr20HI/AAAAAAAAAio/9-9wJIb1K1c/image_thumb9.png?imgmax=800" width="443" height="286" /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Just so I could see an exception that looked more like:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;System.Exception: Hello Exception! &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;amp;#160; at TestExceptionGenerator.Spike.GetException() in …&amp;amp;lt;cut off for brevity&amp;amp;gt; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;amp;#160; at TestExceptionGenerator.Spike.b__0() in …&amp;amp;lt;cut off for brevity&amp;amp;gt; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;amp;#160; at TestExceptionGenerator.Extensions.GetExceptionString(Action action) in …&amp;amp;#160;&amp;amp;#160; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I finally buckled down and threw together a tool for this. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;You can check go check out &amp;lt;a href="http://staxmanade.github.io/ExceptionMessageBeautifier" target="_blank"&amp;gt;Exception Message Beautifier&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; where you can see the sample below.&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://lh3.ggpht.com/-Ts_VJAZqmu4/UrJs9i36LfI/AAAAAAAAAiw/j4jZDVL2Z-Y/s1600-h/image3.png"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img title="image" style="border-left-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px; background-image: none; border-bottom-width: 0px; float: none; padding-top: 0px; padding-left: 0px; margin-left: auto; display: block; padding-right: 0px; border-top-width: 0px; margin-right: auto" border="0" alt="image" src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/-YwT0ZJIBFSA/UrJs93yI9aI/AAAAAAAAAi4/eg2rZr285QE/image_thumb1.png?imgmax=800" width="689" height="354" /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#160;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;I’d like to thank.&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Below are a list of tools/resources I leveraged to put the site together relatively quickly over the weekend.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://codepen.io/" target="_blank"&amp;gt;CodePen.io&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; where I first prototyped/built my site before porting it into the GitHub pages. &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="https://github.com" target="_blank"&amp;gt;GitHub&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for providing us with &amp;lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/" target="_blank"&amp;gt;GitHub Pages&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Made this site a piece of cake to setup. &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://github.com/approvals/Approvals.NodeJS" target="_blank"&amp;gt;Approvals.NodeJS&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; – easily test/verify output. (&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Disclaimer – I created this nodejs port of &amp;lt;a href="http://approvaltests.sourceforge.net/" target="_blank"&amp;gt;Approvals&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for fun a while back and didn’t get around to throwing some polish on the library till now, where I was able to &amp;lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eating_your_own_dog_food" target="_blank"&amp;gt;dog-food&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; it&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;) &amp;lt;img class="wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-smile" style="border-top-style: none; border-bottom-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-left-style: none" alt="Smile" src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/-bZZmkqr5Fqc/UrJs-TZgV2I/AAAAAAAAAjA/22oydAVrbSM/wlEmoticon-smile2.png?imgmax=800" /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://angularjs.org/" target="_blank"&amp;gt;AngularJS&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (a bit overkill for this site, OK TOTAL OVERKILL, but was simple, easy, makes my JS very little, and will allow for easy growth down the road if it needs to.) &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/libraries/devguide" target="_blank"&amp;gt;Google CDN&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for hosting AngularJS &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://google.com/analytics/" target="_blank"&amp;gt;Google Analytics&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (so I can see if anyone cares) &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;If you take a look, find a bug. Submit a GitHub issue and/or a pull request. Or if you find it useful, feel free to let me know.&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;Enjoy!&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;  &lt;/content&gt;
&lt;link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://staxmanade.blogspot.com/feeds/7515836382847059837/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/&gt;
&lt;link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4726251688144615011&amp;amp;postID=7515836382847059837' title='0 Comments'/&gt;
&lt;link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/4726251688144615011/posts/default/7515836382847059837'/&gt;
&lt;link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/4726251688144615011/posts/default/7515836382847059837'/&gt;
&lt;link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://staxmanade.blogspot.com/2013/12/format-your-net-exceptions-to-see.html' title='Format your .Net exceptions to see the StackTrace.'/&gt;
&lt;author&gt;
  &lt;name&gt;Jason Jarrett&lt;/name&gt;
  &lt;uri&gt;https://plus.google.com/112910204617314300568&lt;/uri&gt;
  &lt;email&gt;noreply@blogger.com&lt;/email&gt;
  &lt;gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='32' height='32' src='//lh6.googleusercontent.com/-Lz16PAsLf5Q/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAAAg8/FYSu9U-1tCw/s512-c/photo.jpg'/&gt;
&lt;/author&gt;
&lt;media:thumbnail xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/' url='http://lh5.ggpht.com/-Eo5EyWOkIm0/UrJs9Dr20HI/AAAAAAAAAio/9-9wJIb1K1c/s72-c/image_thumb9.png?imgmax=800' height='72' width='72'/&gt;
&lt;thr:total&gt;0&lt;/thr:total&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>  </entry>
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 2 - Setup Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-2-setup-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-2-setup-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>

<p>Luckily for all of us, this post will be short as the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">Octopress Setup</a> guide is a great place to start. Only additions I have to add are that I&rsquo;ve set this up on both a Mac and a Windows 8 machine.</p>

<p>I had to execute the <code>rake setup_github_pages[repo]</code> on both machines. I should probably <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/PleaseLearnToThinkAboutAbstractions.aspx">look under the abstraction</a> and understand a little deeper &ndash; but I&rsquo;ll have to save that for later. For now I have work to do&hellip;</p>

<h3>On my Mac:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Things worked out quite smoothly on the Mac.</li>
<li>This is where I ran my initial import of the blog (see later posts in the series).</li>
</ul>


<h3>On my Windows 8 machine:</h3>

<ul>
<li>This environment seemed harder to get going</li>
<li>The hardest part on Windows 8 was getting the right combination of ruby, ruby dev kit, and various other dependencies installed. The dependencies for Octopress installation are compatible with later versions of Ruby but the gems needed for blog import are only supported in Ruby 1.9.3 at the time of this writing. Since I don&rsquo;t use Ruby on Windows for anything else, I eventually ended up uninstalling all versions I&rsquo;d previously had (including cleaning up any environment path variables). Re-installing just what I needed and eventually got it working. Another route is to use <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/yari">Scott Muc&rsquo;s yari</a> which allows you to toggle the version of Ruby that you&rsquo;re using.</li>
<li><a href="http://blog.zerosharp.com/setting-up-octopress-on-windows/">Thanks to this post</a> to get started on the windows. Some steps I excluded since I&rsquo;d alredy setup the blog initially on my Mac.</li>
</ul>


<p>Now I can use the power of git to manage my website and blog and I can leverage whatever development tools I would like depending on the platform. If you are new to Octopress it is helpful to study the documentation and structure of the files within your cloned repository. The first thing to note is that you have two branches in the repository: the source branch contains the Ruby scripts and utilities you will use to generate your blog content. The master branch is where your published content will live. The second thing to note is that while you can do the git integrations yourself for deploying the blog, it is best to stick to the RAKE task for deploying your content. This will automate copying your content to the _deploy subdirectory and pushing the update to the master branch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 1 - Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-1-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-1-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After hosting my blog on <a href="http://blogspot.com">BlogSpot.com</a> for over 5 years, it was time to move.</p>

<p>As someone with the development background I have and constantly growing knowledge of the web, it always bugged me that my blog was hosted on BlogSpot.</p>

<p>When I first started blogging over 5 years ago, it was a great starter site. Free, simple, easy to configure and it was a great place to throw content up with very little friction. But my desire to write posts using <a href="http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a>, host my content on a site where I felt like I had complete control, and lets face it, I just wanted a codebase I could tinker with and throw up coding experiments.</p>

<p>I recently completed migration of my <a href="http://staxmanade.blogspot.com">staxmanade.blogspot.com</a> site to its new location here on <a href="http://staxmanade.com">staxmanade.com</a> which is graciously being hosted for free by <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>If you currently have a blog on BlogSpot/Blogger and are interested in migrating to Octopress or any other blog, the following series of posts may be of use.</p>

<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
