<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Developing on Staxmanade]]></title>
  <link href="http://staxmanade.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://staxmanade.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-23T11:54:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://staxmanade.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Jarrett]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 2 - Setup Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-2-setup-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-2-setup-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>

<p>Luckily for all of us, this post will be short as the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">Octopress Setup</a> guide is a great place to start. Only additions I have to add are that I&rsquo;ve set this up on both a Mac and a Windows 8 machine.</p>

<p>I had to execute the <code>rake setup_github_pages[repo]</code> on both machines. I should probably <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/PleaseLearnToThinkAboutAbstractions.aspx">look under the abstraction</a> and understand a little deeper &ndash; but I&rsquo;ll have to save that for later. For now I have work to do&hellip;</p>

<h3>On my Mac:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Things worked out quite smoothly on the Mac.</li>
<li>This is where I ran my initial import of the blog (see later posts in the series).</li>
</ul>


<h3>On my Windows 8 machine:</h3>

<ul>
<li>This environment seemed harder to get going

<ul>
<li>The hardest part on Windows 8 was getting the right combination of ruby, ruby dev kit, and various other dependencies installed. The dependencies for Octopress installation are compatible with later versions of Ruby but the gems needed for blog import are only supported in Ruby 1.9.3 at the time of this writing. Since I don&rsquo;t use Ruby on Windows for anything else, I eventually ended up uninstalling all versions I&rsquo;d previously had (including cleaning up any environment path variables). Re-installing just what I needed and eventually got it working. Another route is to use <a href="https://github.com/scottmuc/yari">Scott Muc&rsquo;s yari</a> which allows you to toggle the version of Ruby that you&rsquo;re using.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://blog.zerosharp.com/setting-up-octopress-on-windows/">Thanks to this post</a> to get started on the windows. Some steps I excluded since I&rsquo;d alredy setup the blog initially on my Mac.</li>
</ul>


<p>Now I can use the power of git to manage my website and blog and I can leverage whatever development tools I would like depending on the platform. If you are new to Octopress it is helpful to study the documentation and structure of the files within your cloned repository. The first thing to note is that you have two branches in the repository: the source branch contains the Ruby scripts and utilities you will use to generate your blog content. The master branch is where your published content will live. The second thing to note is that while you can do the git integrations yourself for deploying the blog, it is best to stick to the RAKE task for deploying your content. This will automate copying your content to the _deploy subdirectory and pushing the update to the master branch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating From BlogSpot to Octopress - Part 1 - Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-1-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T20:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://staxmanade.com/2014/04/migrating-blogspot-to-octopress-part-1-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After hosting my blog on <a href="http://blogspot.com">BlogSpot.com</a> for over 5 years, it was time to move.</p>

<p>As someone with the development background I have and constantly growing knowledge of the web, it always bugged me that my blog was hosted on BlogSpot.</p>

<p>When I first started blogging over 5 years ago, it was a great starter site. Free, simple, easy to configure and it was a great place to throw content up with very little friction. But my desire to write posts using <a href="http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a>, host my content on a site where I felt like I had complete control, and lets face it, I just wanted a codebase I could tinker with and throw up coding experiments.</p>

<p>I recently completed migration of my <a href="http://staxmanade.blogspot.com">staxmanade.blogspot.com</a> site to its new location here on <a href="http://staxmanade.com">staxmanade.com</a> which is graciously being hosted for free by <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>If you currently have a blog on BlogSpot/Blogger and are interested in migrating to Octopress or any other blog, the following series of posts may be of use.</p>

<p>


	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	





	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	


<div class="seriesNote">
	<p>This article is <strong>Part 0</strong> of <strong>0</strong> in a series about <strong></strong>.</p>
	<ul>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	</ul>
</div>


</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
